The next several topics will take us through
working with and building functions. Though
it makes sense to build a function and then work
with its particulars, the exam topics start with
running a function and then building one, which
is an approach that aligns with practical usage,
so that's how we'll proceed. First, let’s
define a function. A function is a block
of code that can be called multiple times
within an app. Functions are best used when
you have a process that needs repeating. A
real-life example, outside of programming,
can be a daily workout routine one has. Instead
of writing down the same thing to do each day,
one could write down the set of workout
steps once and then, several days a week,
have instructions to do that block of
exercises. Let’s put this idea of functions
into a programming example related to gaming.
A game could often need to multiply a score
and a multiplier. In this 421-signatures file,
a function named total score uses two values,
known as arguments, stored as variables, that
multiply a score, using this multiplier is on
line 2. I will get into the anatomy of a function
over the next few videos, but I want you to focus
on the print statements on lines 4 and 5. Lines 4
and 5 see print statements that call the function,
using scores and multipliers as arguments. I will
run this code, and the two numbers are multiplied
for both of the print statements. Functions are
an integral part of programming as they save time
and, as code does need to be repeated, functions
also reduce the number of errors within code.